Guide to the Collection of Advertisements that Depict American History
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Collection of advertisements that depict American history.
1870-1994
1887-1970
WA MSS S-2622
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.28
(14 boxes)
This collection consists of collecting cards, advertising cards, sticker books, sheet music, and printed ephemera that document popular culture images of the United States and North America as viewed chiefly by countries throughout Europe, including France, Great Britain, Belgium, Germany, and Italy. The collection provides depictions of American subjects and themes from primarily European viewpoints used by companies to advertise their products or as premiums accompanying products. Subjects particularly well represented include Indians of North America and the American West, as well as natural landscapes and historical events, such as national parks and the American Civil War. Prominent individuals represented in the collection include United States presidents, particularly George Washington and Abraham Lincoln, and historical figures including Daniel Boone, Sitting Bull, Kit Carson, and Wyatt Earp.
General note
Title devised by cataloger.
General note
This is an open collection to which additions are expected. Consequently, it is organized by accession, with the contents of each accession arranged in parallel fashion.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Kevin Jackson on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2009-2010.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of collecting cards, advertising cards, sticker books, sheet music, and printed ephemera, which document popular culture images of the United States and North America as viewed chiefly by countries throughout Europe, including France, Great Britain, Belgium, Germany, and Italy. Overall, the collection provides depictions of American subjects and themes used by companies to advertise their products. Images in the collection provide especially rich representations of Indians of North America and the American West, as well as natural landscapes and historical events, such as national parks and the American Civil War. Prominent individuals represented in the collection include United States presidents, particularly George Washington and Abraham Lincoln, and historical figures, including Daniel Boone, Sitting Bull, Kit Carson, and Wyatt Earp.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. 2009 Acquisition, circa 1870-1988. II. 2010 Acquisition, 1870-1994.
Advertising -- Europe; Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Popular culture -- Pictorial works; Presidents -- United States -- Pictorial works; United States -- Pictorial works; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Advertising cards; Chromolithographs; Printed ephemera; Sheet music; Sticker books; Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820 -- Pictorial works; Carson, Kit, 1809-1868 -- Pictorial works; Earp, Wyatt, 1848-1929 -- Pictorial works; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 ( Pictorial works); Sitting Bull, 1831-1890 -- Portraits; Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Pictorial works
- 2009 Acquisition, circa 1870-1988; Series I; 158
  Arrangement
  Arranged in five subseries: Collecting Cards, Advertising Cards, Sticker Books, Sheet Music, and Printed Ephemera.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of collecting cards, advertising cards, sticker books, sheet music, and printed ephemera, which document popular culture images of the United States and North America, and the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library acquired in 2009.
  - Collecting Cards
    Arranged alphabetically by company and then chronologically.
    Collecting cards issued singly or in sets. Some cards include advertising or accompanied a product as a premium.
    - A. & B.C. Gum
      - Flags of the World, 1959; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Tobacco Company
      - Types of Nations, 1911; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Astra Margarine
      - Les Indiens (Indians), circa 1930; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Axa Margarine
      - Amérique Occidentale/West Amerika (Western America), circa 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barratt & Co.
      - Animals in the Service of Man, 1964; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Biesolt & Locke Sewing Machines
      - Religiöse Gebräuche (Religious Rites), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Carreras Ltd.
      - Figures of Fiction, 1924; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cavanders Ltd.
      - Peeps Into Many Lands, 1928; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chocolat de Guyenne
      - Les Costumes: Renaissance a Nos Jours (Costumes: Renaissance to Today), circa 1920; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chocolat Félix Potin
      - Les Grands Explorateurs (The Great Explorers), circa 1900; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Chocolat Guérin-Boutron
      - Auteurs Célébres, Principales Oevres (Celebrated Authors, Principal Scenes), circa 1895; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Chasses et Pêches (Fishing and Hunting), circa 1895; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Les Costumes, Antiquité a Moyen Âge (Costumes, Antiquity to Middle Ages), circa 1895; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Les Grands Explorateurs (The Great Explorers), circa 1895; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Les Bienfaiteurs de l'Humanite (The Benefactors of Humanity), circa 1905; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Fleurs-Pays (Flowers by Country), circa 1905; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Les Mammiferes (The Mammals), circa 1950; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Le Tour Du Monde en 84 Étapes (Around the World in 84 Steps), circa 1905; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Chocolat Meurisse
      - Costumes Nationaux/Nationale Klederdrachten (National Costumes), circa 1945; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Chocolat Poulain
      - La Nature et Ses Merveilles (Nature and Its Wonders), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Tour du Monde d'un Naturaliste (World Tour of a Naturalist), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chocolat Unicol
      - Collection la Poste/Verzameling de Post, circa 1935; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Chocolaterie d'Aiguebelle
      - Le Monde des Plantes (The World of Plants), circa 1900; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Club Member Cigarettes
      - Indian Blanket Weaver, circa 1925; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Franklin, Davey & Co.
      - Children of all Nations, 1939; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gartmann-Chocolade
      - Amerikan Völkertypen (Types of American People), circa 1900-1910; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Tragen der Kinder Bei Verschiedenen Völkern (Children's Clothing of Different Nations), circa 1900-1910; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - H. Laas & Cie
      - Amérique du Nord (North America), circa 1890; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Les Races Humaines (Human Races), circa 1890; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hassan Cigarettes
      - The World's Greatest Explorers, 1910; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Helmar Turkish Cigarettes/Turkish Trophies Cigarettes
      - Costumes and Scenery for All the Countries of the World, circa 1900; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hoadley's Chocolates
      - Wild West Series, 1938; 50 cards (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - I. Masclet
      - Le Capitole de Washington, circa 1890; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - John Player & Sons
      - British Empire Series, 1904; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Riders of the World, 1905; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Famous Beauties, 1937; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Lavazza
      - Vecchio Far West (Old Wild West), 1951; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Le Razze Umane (The Human Race), 1956; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Usi Strani di Strana Gente: I Diavoli Rossi Della Terre Rosse (Strange Uses of Strange People: The Red Devils of the Red Land), 1959; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Liebig Extract of Meat Company
      - Christophe Colomb (Christopher Columbus), 1887; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Scènes des Oevres de Fenimore Cooper (Scenes of James Fenimore Cooper ), 1897; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Berühmte Felsen (Famous Rocks), 1902; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - La Case de l'Oncle Tom (Uncle Tom's Cabin), 1904; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Au Mexique (Mexico), 1908; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - La Coltivazone del Contone (Cultivation of Cotton), 1909; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Kinderspel en Poppen in Verscheidene Landen (Children and Dolls in Several Countries), 1911; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Peaux Rouges - Faiseur de Pluie (Redskins - Rainmaker), circa 1911; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Histoire des Etats-Unis (History of the United States ), 1938; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - La Vallée de la Morte (Death Valley), 1940; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Il Fuoco Presso I Selvaggi (Fire Among the Natives), 1940; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Coutumes de Mariages Exotiques (Exotic Wedding Customs), 1941; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Le Chant de Hiawatha (The Song of Hiawatha), 1948; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Geschiedenis der Verenigde Staten (History of the United States), 1956; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Indiens des Plaines et Des Bois de l'Amerique du Nord (Indians of the Plains and Woods of North America), 1956; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Indiens Pueblos et Totémistes de l'Amerique du Nord (Pueblo and Totem Indians of North America), 1956; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Historie de Mexique (History of Mexico), 1958; 6 cards (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Comment Elles Portent Leur Enfant (How Children are Carried,), 1959; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Corps Expéditionnaires Belges (Belgian Expeditionary Forces), 1962; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Le Culle nel Mondo (Beds in the World), 1967; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Le Grandi Sfide (The Grand Battles), 1972; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Major Drapkin & Co.
      - Puzzle Pictures, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - Girls of Many Lands, 1929; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Nostalgia Reprints
      - Celebrated American Indian Chiefs, 1988; 47 cards (Box 1, Folder 63)
        Reprints of cards distributed by Allen & Ginter in 1888.
    - Ogden's Cigarettes
      - Picturesque People of the Empire, 1927; 4 cards (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Peter Jackson (Overseas) Ltd.
      - Speed - Through the Ages, 1937; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Ringtons Limited
      - Head-Dresses of the World, 1973; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Royal Bengals Little Cigars
      - Men of History, 2nd Series, circa 1910-1912; 15 cards (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Rosan Printing Corporation
      - U.S. Army in Action, 1953; 64 cards (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Sidam
      - World Locations, circa 1960; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Thés Sarah - Poivres Sarah
      - Les Grands Explorateurs (The Great Explorers), circa 1895; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Topps
      - Roundup, 1956; 80 cards (Box 1, Folder 71)
      - Civil War News, 1961; 88 cards (Box 1, Folder 72)
        Includes fifteen reproductions of Confederate States of America Currency
    - Typhoo Tea Ltd.
      - British Empire at Work, 1925; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 73)
      - Paper Models, 1927; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - Important Industries of the British Empire, 1939; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 75)
      - Travel Through the Ages, 1962; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - United Services Manufacturing Company Limited
      - Ancient Warriors, 1938; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - W.A. & A.C. Churchman Cigarettes
      - Pipes of the World, 1912; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 78)
      - Curious Dwellings, 1926; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 79)
      - Warriors of All Nations, 1929; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - W.D. & H.O. Wills
      - Time & Money in Different Countries, 1908; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 81)
      - Riders of the World, 1926; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - W. Duke & Sons
      - Battle Scenes (American Civil War), 1887; 25 cards (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Wagner & Co.
      - Menschenrassen (Races), 1928; 1 card (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Advertising Cards
    Arranged alphabetically by merchant, manufacturer, or product.
    Cards distributed chiefly in France by merchants or manufacturers to advertise or promote their business or product.
    Each folder contains a single advertising card, except where noted.
    - Archambault Jeune, Angers, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Arlatte & Cie. - Chiorée Bleu Argent, Cambrai, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Au Bon Marche, Paris, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Badoit, Saint-Galmier, France, circa 1895 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Biscuits Pernot, Dijon, France, circa 1899 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Boucherie Sedaine, Paris, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Café Instantané Robertet, Grasse, France, circa 1875-1887 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Chaussures Bourdais, Tours, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Chocolat Félix Potin, Paris, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Chocolat d'Aiguebelle, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Chocolat Guérin-Boutron, Paris, France, circa 1890; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Chocolat Ibled, Paris, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Chocolat Klaus, Paris, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Chocolat Louit, Bordeaux, France, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Chocolat Moreuil, Paris, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Clark & Co., Paris, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Désiré Ikelmer, Paris, France, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - A l'Époque, Paris, France, circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Huntley & Palmers Biscuits, Reading and London, Great Britain, circa 1880; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - La Kabiline Dye, France, circa 1895 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Lefèvre-Utile Biscuit Co., Nantes, France, circa 1890; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Maison de la Belle Jardinière, Paris, France, circa 1870 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Maison de la Pointe, Saint-Eustache, Paris, France, circa 1878; 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Maison Leconte-Collette, Lille, France, circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Mon Meyer, Tonnerre, France, circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Noviant, Nancy, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - P. Lebeault & Cie., Paris, France, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Paillettes Maire, Paris, France, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Poitel, Le Mans, France, circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Van Leckwyck & Co., Rotterdam, Holland, circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Vincent Fils Ainè, Saint-Étienne, France, circa 1878 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Unidentified, circa 1880-1900; 14 cards (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Sticker Books
    Arranged alphabetically by publisher and then chronologically.
    Books, generally intended for children, with pages that feature illustrations of stickers affixed in formerly blank spaces.
    Each folder a single sticker book, except where single or multiple stickers without a sticker book are noted.
    - Agência Portuguesa de Revistas
      - West, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Artis - Brussels
      - Harriet Beecher-Stowe, La Case de l'Oncle Tom (Uncle Tom's Cabin), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 118)
        French translation by Jean Voellmy, with illustrations by Hugo Laubi.
    - Belgian Chewing Gum
      - Far West Album, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Casino
      - Jojo et Louisette Voyage Autour du Monde: Amérique (Travel Around the World: America), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Chocolade Martougin
      - Buffalo-Bill, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 121)
      - Sitting Bull, de Indiaanse Napoleon (Sitting Bull, the Indian Napoleon), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Chocolat Pupier
      - l'Amerique du Nord (North America), circa 1968; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Cocorico
      - Willis Lindquist, John Alan Maxwell, and Charles Bellows, l'Encyclopédie par le Timbre - Kit Carson, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 124)
        French edition of Willis Lindquist, The Golden Stamp Book of Kit Carson (New York: Simon & Schuster, 1956).
    - Golden Press
      - Thomas K. Ford and Mel Crawford. The Golden Stamp Book of Presidents of the United States., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Gordon Bread Company
      - Nature's Splendor, circa 1950; 2 stickers (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - International Edugraphic
      - American History: Discovery Through the American Revolution, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - John Player & Sons
      - Military Uniforms of the British Empire Overseas, 1937; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Meurisse Chocolade
      - De Wonderlÿke gebarentaal der Indianen (The Marvelous Indian Sign Language), circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Nestlé
      - Series 59. Scènes de la Vie Indienne (Scenes from Indian Life), by K. F. Berg, 1956; 12 stamps on 1 sheet (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Nestlé, Peter, Cailler, Kohler
      - Album Chocola's, circa 1953; 1 sticker (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Simon & Schuster
      - Jeanette Eaton and Harper Johnson, The Golden Stamp Book of George Washington, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 132)
      - Willis Lindquist and Edwin Schmidt, The Golden Play Book of Pirate Stamps, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 133)
      - Irwin Shapiro and Nino Cabre, The Golden Stamp Book of Westward Ho, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 134)
      - Irwin Shapiro and Douglas Gorsline, The Golden Stamp Book of Abraham Lincoln, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 135)
      - Willis Lindquist and Peter Bruchard, The Golden Stamp Book of Discoveries and Explorers, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 136)
      - Louis Ramón and Al Schmidt, The Golden Stamp Book of Daniel Boone, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 137)
      - Monica Hill and Mel Crawford, The Golden Stamp Book: The Life and Legend of Wyatt Earp, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Sheet Music
    Arranged chronologically,
    Music printed on unbound sheets of paper with illustrations and content that reflect American themes.
    - Theodore Bonheur, Across the Plains: Indian Ride (London: W. Paxton & Co.), 1915 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Neil Moret (pseudonym of Charles N. Daniels), Silverheels (London: Francis Day & Hunter), 1915 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Harry H. Williams and Egbert Van Alstyne, In the Land of the Buffalo (London: Francis Day & Hunter), 1907 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Printed Ephemera
    Arranged alphabetically by format and then chronologically.
    Printed ephemera consisting of cigar bands, composition books, a counter card advertisement, and chromolithograph cutouts of American Indians.
    - Cigar Bands
      Narrow paper bands that originally encircled a cigar with illustrations, chiefly depicting Indians of North America.
      - Cogétama, Ghent, Belgium, circa 1955-1970; 216 cigar bands (Box 4, Folder 142-150)
      - Havana Karakter, Netherlands, circa 1970; 24 cigar bands (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Coloring Sheets
      - Nestlé chez les Peaux-Rouges, 1930; 1 sheet (Box 4, Folder 152)
        An outline drawing that depicts an American Indian holding a container of powdered chocolate.
    - Composition Books
      Stock-bound notebooks manufactured in Italy with cover illustrations that depict subjects from the American West.
      Each folder contains a book, except where noted.
      - A. Pizzi, Milan, Italy, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - C.B.D., Milan, Italy, circa 1955; 2 books (Box 4, Folder 154)
      - Cartiere Paolo Pigna, Alzano Lombardo, Italy, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 155)
      - Sterziana, Milan, Italy, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 156)
        Includes school of an Italian student and marks by a teacher in March-April 1957
    - Counter Card Advertisements
      - Crüwell-Tabak, circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 157)
        A cardboard point of purchase sign that depicts an American Indian smoking a calumet.
    - Chromolithograph Cutouts of American Indians, circa 1880-1890; 7 cutouts (Box 4, Folder 158)
- 2010 Acquisition, 1870-1994; Series II; 284
  This series consists of collecting cards, advertising cards, sticker books, sheet music, and printed ephemera, which document popular culture images of the United States and North America, and the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library acquired in 2010.
  - Collecting Cards
    - A. & B. C. Gum
      - Battle, 1966; 73 cards (Box 5, Folder 159-160)
      - The Legend of Custer, 1968; 54 cards (Box 5, Folder 161-162)
    - American Tobacco Company
      - Cowboy Series, 1909; 49 cards (Box 5, Folder 163)
        General note
        Cards accompanied Hassan Cigarettes.
        Lacks unpublished card of a poker shooting scene, which the manufacturer deemed too violent.
      - Indian life in the 60's, 1910; 50 cards (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Anglo Confectionery Ltd.
      - Wild West, 1970; 66 cards (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Arlatte & Cie.
      - Untitled Series, circa 1900; 6 cards (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Aviatik-Zigarettenfabrik
      - Die Indianer, Wie Sie Wirklich Waren (The Indians, As They Really Were), 1936; 1 card (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Barratt & Co. Ltd.
      - Wild West, 1959; 36 cards (Box 5, Folder 168)
      - The Wild West, 1961; 24 cards (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Bon-Point
      - Unititled series, circa 1930; 1 card (Box 5, Folder 170)
        Cards accompanied Sirop de Deschiens à l'Hémoglobine
      - Indiens Peaux-Rouges (Indian Redskins), circa 1950; 6 cards (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Bowman Gum Haelan Laboratories Inc.
      - U.S. Navy Victories, 1954; 48 cards (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - British-American Tobacco Company Ltd.
      - Indian Chiefs, 1930; 50 cards (Box 5, Folder 173)
      - Wild West, 1932; 100 cards (Box 6, Folder 174)
        Cards accompanied packs of Gold Dollar Zigaretten.
      - In Prärie und Urwald (In Prairie and Forest), 1934; 100 cards (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Brooke Bond Oxo Ltd.
      - Adventurers & Explorers, 1973; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Brooke Bond Tea Ltd.
      - Transport through the Ages, 1966; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Carreras Ltd.
      - Highwaymen, 1924; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Cavanders Ltd.
      - Peeps Into Many Lands, 1928; 6 cards (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Chocolat Guérin-Boutron, Paris, France
      - Fleurs Avec Pays d'Origine (Flowers With Country of Origin), circa 1900; 2 cards (Box 6, Folder 180)
      - Les Bienfaiteurs de l'humanité (Benefactors of Mankind), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Chocolat Poulain
      - Les Ponts Pittoresques (Scenic Bridges), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 182)
      - Unidentified series, circa 1900; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 183)
      - Unidentified series, circa 1900; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 184)
      - l'Amerique du Nord (North America), circa 1968; 214 cards (Box 14, Folder 185)
        Includes album.
    - Chocolates Amatller
      - Banderas del Universo (Flags of the Universe), circa 1920; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - La Guerra Europea - 1917 (The European War - 1917), circa 1920; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Juanito Valiente: Aventura del Niño que No Creció Jamás (Juanito Valiente: Adventure of the Boy who Would Never Grow Up), circa 1928; 25 cards (Box 6, Folder 188)
      - Grandes Cacerias por Segrelles (Big Hunt for Segrelles), circa 1930; 5 cards (Box 6, Folder 189)
      - Hombres Eminentes (Eminent Men), circa 1935; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Chocolates de Bernardo Alcover
      - Colección Zoológica (Zoo), circa 1900; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Chocolates Riucord
      - Exploradores (Explorers), circa 1935; 3 cards (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Cichorien-Caffee-Fabrik Daniel Voelcker
      - Lastesel Belm Trunke aus Mamillarien (Donkeys Last Drink from Watermelons), circa 1910; 1 card (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Como Confectionery Products (London) Ltd.
      - Como's History of the Wild West, 1963; 50 cards (Box 6, Folder 194)